Sometimes you need to verify
s vezes, voc precisa verificar um mtodo no teste que
a method on the test that is returning the right type. So let's
est retornando o tipo correto. Ento, vamos dar
take a look at this CustomerController class in the fundamentals
uma olhada nesta classe CustomerController na
folder. This is the simplified example of a controller
pasta fundamentals. Este  o exemplo simplificado de
in ASP.NET MVC applications. If you don't have experience
um controlador no ASP. Aplicaes NET MVC. Se voc no tem
with ASP.NET MVC it doesn't matter. So let's see what is
experincia com o ASP. NET MVC isso no importa. Ento vamos ver
happening here. You have this class called ActionResult,
o que est acontecendo aqui. Voc tem essa classe
and this class has two derivatives, you have NotFound
chamada ActionResult, e essa classe tem duas derivadas,
which is derived from ActionResult, and also
voc tem NotFound que  derivado de ActionResult
Ok. So, in our controller class, you have
e tambm Ok. Ento, na nossa classe controladora, voc
this method, GetCustomer, gets an ID. If ID is 0
tem esse mtodo, GetCustomer, obtendo um ID. Se ID for 0,
it returns a new instance of the NotFound class.
ele retornar uma nova instncia da classe NotFound.
Otherwise, it returns a new instance of the Okay class.
Caso contrrio, retorna uma nova instncia da classe Okay.
So because both these classes derive from action result,
Portanto, como essas duas classes derivam do resultado da ao, o tipo
the return type of this method is ActionResult. So,
de retorno desse mtodo  ActionResult. Ento, quantos testes precisamos
how many tests do we need here, we need two tests, because we
aqui, precisamos de dois testes, porque temos dois
have two execution paths, if ID is 0,
caminhos de execuo, se ID  0, queremos
we want to make sure that the object that this method returns is
ter certeza de que o objeto que este
a NotFound object, otherwise, it's an
mtodo retorna  um objeto NotFound, caso contrrio,
Ok object, so, back in our unit testing
um objeto Ok Ento, de volta ao
project, I'm going to add a new test class,
nosso projeto de teste de unidade, vou adicionar
called CustomerControllerTest.
uma nova classe de teste, chamada CustomerControllerTest.
Apply
Aplique ao atributo TestFixture
to TestFixture attribute with
com um mtodo de
a Test method. So,
teste. Portanto, o
the method is GetCustomer, one scenario is
mtodo  GetCustomer,
IdIsZero,
um cenrio
should return ReturnNotFound.
IdIsZero, deve retornar ReturnNotFound.
And of course the other scenario is
E, claro, o outro
public void GetCustomer
cenrio  public void
IdIsNotZero, it should ReturnOk.
GetCustomer IdIsNotZero, deve ReturnOk.
Now, in this lecture,
Agora, nesta palestra, vou implementar apenas um desses
I'm just going to implement one of these test methods, and I leave the other two
mtodos de teste e deixo os outros dois
as an exercise. So we create controller object
como um exerccio. Assim, criamos
a new CustomerController,
o objeto controller um novo
and call GetCustomer,
CustomerController e chamamos GetCustomer e
and pass 0 as the argument.
passamos 0 como argumento.
We get the result, now we want to Assert that this result
Obtemos o resultado, agora queremos afirmar que esse resultado
is a NotFound object. In NUnit
um objeto NotFound. No NUnit existem duas
there are two ways to write such Assertions. One way is like this:
maneiras de escrever tais asseres. Uma maneira
Assert That result
a seguinte: Assert Esse resultado
Is TypeOf, and this is a generate
TypeOf, e este  um mtodo
method, so we supply the generate argument, in this case, Not
generate, portanto, fornecemos o argumento generate,
Found. This is the Assertion that you would use
neste caso, Not Found. Esta  a afirmao que voc
most of the time. We have another way
usaria na maior parte do tempo. Temos outra maneira de
to write this Assertion, so let me duplicate this line,
escrever essa afirmao, ento deixe-me duplicar essa
instead of the type of method, we use, Instance
linha, em vez do tipo de mtodo,
Of. So, what is the difference? This
usamos Instance Of. Ento qual  a diferena? Este mtodo
InstanceOf method, means the result
InstanceOf, significa o resultado e o objeto
and NotFound object, are one of it's derivatives, whereas
NotFound, so um de seus derivados, enquanto
TypeOf, ensures that the result is exactly
que TypeOf, garante que o resultado seja
NotFound object. So, this
exatamente o objeto NotFound. Ento, isso significa que o
means the result should be a NotFound object, and
resultado deve ser um objeto NotFound e esta declarao
this Assertion means the result should be a NotFound object.
significa que o resultado deve ser um objeto NotFound.
or one of its derivatives.
ou um dos seus derivados.
In this particular implementation, I'm going to use
Nesta implementao especfica, usarei a primeira Assero, porque
the first Assertion, because I want to make sure the result is exactly a Not
quero ter certeza de que o resultado seja
Found object. But be aware of this other
exatamente um objeto Not Found. Mas esteja ciente dessa outra
way to write this Assertion, maybe you will need these in some particular scenario
maneira de escrever essa afirmao, talvez voc precise delas em
in your application. So I'm going to comment this out because we don't need it.
algum cenrio especfico em sua aplicao. Ento, vou comentar isso porque no precisamos disso.